https://www.nationalcac.org/privacy-policy/

HomeLocal Services
Local Services offered to Huntsville/Madison County families and children.
Intervention ServicesIntervention ProgramsForensic Interview ServicesMedical ServicesFamily and Victim Advocacy ServicesMental Health ServicesMultidisciplinary TeamChild and Family Resources
Prevention ServicesPrevention ProgramsStop Child Abuse and Neglect (SCAN)Child Sexual Abuse Prevention for AdultsHealthy FamiliesCase Management ServicesParenting ClassesPartnership in ParentingParent Library
Get Involved
Get InvolvedLearn More
A child's life......should be carefree and fun.
No child should ever experience abuse. All over the world and right here in our community, children are abused everyday. In 2018, over 8,000 Madison County children used our local services but only because of our amazing donors and volunteers. Find out more about how YOU can get involved!
Events
EventsAim for Advocacy Sporting Clay EventOctober 16, 2020Coffee for KidsJoin us November 13, 2020 for our Fall Tour at 9:00 a.m.Superheroes ShindigThank you for your support!
Training Services
About NCAC Training CenterThe NCAC Training Center is located on the campus of the National Children's Advocacy Center in Huntsville, Alabama and is one of the leading providers of quality training for professionals working with abused children and their families.
NCAC Training CenterTraining OpportunitiesForensic Interviewing of Children Training Advanced Forensic Interviewing TrainingExtended Forensic Interview TrainingVictim Advocacy TrainingForensic Interviews at TrialConducting Child Abuse Investigations TrainingCustomized On-Location TrainingInternational Training and Consultation
Online TrainingNCAC Virtual Training CenterOnline Training CatalogWebinarMentoring and Consultation Groups for Child Forensic InterviewersBuilding Forensic Interviewing Skills Online TrainingConsultation Group for Supervisors of Forensic InterviewersOther Online Training Providers
Other TrainingsInternational Symposium on Child AbuseSouthern Regional Children's Advocacy Center (SRCAC)Takeaway TuesdayProsecutor's Brief
Media
Newsroom
NewsroomNewsOut and About
Media Tool KitMedia Tool Kit
CALiO™ Library
CALiO™ (Child Abuse Library Online)
The Child Abuse Library Online (CALiO™) is the largest online resource library for child maltreatment professionals.
CALiO™ contains professional knowledge, educational materials, full-text publications, and over 4000 keyword-searchable resources.
This library is freely accessible to anyone and provides resources to professionals, students, educational institutions, and more.
Learn More
About
About NCACThe National Children’s Advocacy Center (NCAC), located in Huntsville, Alabama, revolutionized the United States’ response to child sexual abuse. Since its creation in 1985, the NCAC has served as a model for the 950+ Children’s Advocacy Centers (CACs) now operating in the United States and in more than 34 countries throughout the world.
About UsHistoryMultidisciplinary TeamNCAC Campus TourExecutive DirectorExecutive TeamBoard of Directors and StakeholdersNational SpokespersonAnnual ReportsCareersContact Us
ResourcesAbout Child AbuseFor KidsFor ParentsFor ProfessionalsNCAC Position Papers
Privacy Policy
Your privacy is important to the National Children’s Advocacy Center (NCAC). This statement describes the NCAC’s privacy practices for its website, including what type of information is gathered and tracked, how the information is used, and with whom the information is shared.
Personal Information
You can visit www.nationalcac.org without revealing any information about yourself. However, to access certain portions of the website, you may have to submit information such as user-id and password, or to access some services we provide, you may have to provide personal information such as your name, address, and e-mail address.
To access our transaction programs, we may ask you for your address and/or credit card information. When registering for conferences, trainings, webinars or workshops via the NCAC website or through the services hosted by another service provider, we may also ask you to choose a security question to answer (such as your mother’s maiden name or your pet’s name). This required information is necessary for us to process transactions, issue a new password if you forget or lose your password, protect you against credit card fraud, and to contact you should the need arise in administering your account.
Information security and quality
We intend to protect the quality and integrity of your personally identifiable information. We have implemented appropriate physical, technical, and organizational measures, such as using industry accepted encryption for transmission of credit card information, to help keep your information secure, accurate, current, and complete. When you submit sensitive information via the NCAC website, your information is protected both online and offline.
We will maintain the information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information.
Analytics
We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our website, such as Google Analytics. We automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse our website, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to our website, and information about how you interact with our website.
Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared by Google Analytics with other Google services.
For more information, ways to opt-out of Google Analytics activity collection, and information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: https://policies.google.com/
Cookies
We sometimes use cookies to collect anonymous information from visits to our websites to help us provide better service. We may use this data to analyze trends and statistics and to help us provide better customer service, but we do so in ways that keep the information anonymous. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your system. To learn more about setting browser cookie preferences, review the help section within your browser.
Disclosure to third parties
We will only share personally identifiable information with a third party when the individual submitting this information has permitted us to do so, or if we are required by law to do so. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact. We will not sell or rent this information. See below for more information regarding third-party vendors that NCAC uses, or to opt out of these services:
Absorb, CALiO, Constant Contact, CVENT, Donor Perfect, GoDaddy, NCAtrak, Square, WordPress
Children's Online Privacy Protection
While little, if any, of the NCAC website, is directed towards children, we are committed to complying with applicable laws and requirements, such as the United States' Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).
The NCAC website contains links to other websites. NCAC is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.
Notification of Changes
This privacy statement was last updated on January 18, 2019. We may update this privacy policy from time to time to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal, or regulatory reasons.
You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do so at any time by contacting us:
• By email: webmaster@nationalcac.org
• By visiting this page on our website: https://www.nationalcac.org/contact-us/
• By mail: National Children’s Advocacy Center, 210 Pratt Avenue NE, Huntsville, Alabama 35801
210 Pratt Ave NE, Huntsville, AL 35801
256-533-KIDS (5437)
© 2020 National Children's Advocacy Center Privacy Policy
|
Accessibility
Translate »
COVID-19 RESPONSE
RACIAL INEQUITY RESPONSE
